<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Api Management on chamilad.github.io</title>
    <link>https://chamilad.github.io/tags/api-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Api Management on chamilad.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:49:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chamilad.github.io/tags/api-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Design a WSO2 Docker Image</title>
      <link>https://chamilad.github.io/post/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamilad.github.io/post/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</guid>
      <description>What should be your concerns for WSO2 on Docker? Deploying WSO2 products on Containerized platforms is a well-tested well-resourced activity. There are various resources available to deploy WSO2 products on Docker, Kubernetes, CloudFoundry, AWS ECS, and Apache Mesos, both officially and unofficially. However, designing a Docker image so that optimal non-functional traits like performance, operational efficiency, and security is a separate topic in itself.
Docker, being both a DSL and a utility tool for Container image packaging, can be written in several different ways keeping various operational goals in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD APIs with WSO2 API Manager</title>
      <link>https://chamilad.github.io/post/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 03:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamilad.github.io/post/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</guid>
      <description>How to do continuous integration and continuous delivery of APIs with WSO2 API Manager WSO2 API Manager, the only Open Source Leader in API Management Solutions in Forrester Wave, packs in a wide range of advanced API Management features that covers a number of end user stories. Through customization introduced to the extension points available throughout the product, WSO2 API Manager can be adopted to almost all API Management scenarios imaginable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
