<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Api Management on chamila.dev</title>
    <link>https://chamila.dev/tags/api-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Api Management on chamila.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 18:15:37 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://chamila.dev/tags/api-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Design a WSO2 Docker Image</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-should-be-your-concerns-for-wso2-ondocker&#34;&gt;What should be your concerns for WSO2 on Docker?&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image_0.jpeg#layoutTextWidth&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chamila.dev/thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes-4e9a77b3377d&#34;&gt;Deploying WSO2 products on Containerized platforms&lt;/a&gt; is a well-tested well-resourced activity. There are various resources available to deploy WSO2 products on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/docker-apim&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/kubernetes-apim/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/pivotal-cf-apim&#34;&gt;CloudFoundry&lt;/a&gt;, AWS ECS, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/dcos-apim&#34;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, both officially and unofficially. However, designing a Docker image so that optimal non-functional traits like performance, operational efficiency, and security is a separate topic in itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image_1.png#layoutTextWidth&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Options available to obtain WSO2 products other than downloading the Zip file itself (https://wso2.com/api-management/install/)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker, being both a DSL and a utility tool for Container image packaging, can be written in several different ways keeping various operational goals in mind. These approaches vary from an all files and configs pre-baked end to another end where almost everything, except a tiny helper layer, being mounted at Container run-time. However, not all these approaches are suitable for a WSO2 deployment, and figuring out these details can be a daunting task, especially at an earlier phase of the deployment. Therefore, it’s important to have a set of common &lt;strong&gt;guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;that can help determine which approach to take in each case. I emphasize the word &lt;strong&gt;guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; because these are only them, not hard rules or must-do’s in every deployment. There is freedom for the user to stray away, as long as the compromises made in doing so are understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD APIs with WSO2 API Manager</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 03:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-do-continuous-integration-and-continuous-delivery-of-apis-with-wso2-apimanager&#34;&gt;How to do continuous integration and continuous delivery of APIs with WSO2 API Manager&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wso2.com/api-management/&#34;&gt;WSO2 API Manager&lt;/a&gt;, the only &lt;a href=&#34;https://wso2.com/resources/analyst-reports/the-forrester-wave-api-management-solutions-q4-2018/?utm_source=bannerprodpg&amp;amp;utm_medium=mailer&amp;amp;utm_campaign=forrester_wave_apim_2018B2&#34;&gt;Open Source Leader in API Management Solutions in Forrester Wave&lt;/a&gt;, packs in a wide range of advanced API Management features that covers a number of end user stories. Through customization introduced to the extension points available throughout the product, WSO2 API Manager can be adopted to almost all API Management scenarios imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
