<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Computing on chamila.dev</title>
    <link>https://chamila.dev/tags/cloud-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud Computing on chamila.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 06:44:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chamila.dev/tags/cloud-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on Observability for Dynamic Organizations — Part 2</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-10-25_primer-on-observability-for-dynamic-organizationspart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 06:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-10-25_primer-on-observability-for-dynamic-organizationspart-2/</guid>
      <description>What should an Observability Framework address? In the previous post, we measured the temperature of the water on what Observability is and why it should be a first class consideration in system design. Let’s explore the possibility of a structured approach for designing observable systems.
 Massive industrial process of Sugar production where the mechanics are mostly literally behind 10-inch steel walls   Why should there be a structured approach?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on Observability for Dynamic Organizations — Part 1</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-08-21_primer-on-observability-for-dynamic-organizations-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 04:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-08-21_primer-on-observability-for-dynamic-organizations-part-1/</guid>
      <description>A introduction to the buzzword and the rationale for implementing it What is Observability? Before we dive in to the waters, we need to define what observability is. Let’s go for some tweets first.
Monitoring is for operating software/systems
Instrumentation is for writing software
Observability is for understanding systems
&amp;mdash; Charity Majors (@mipsytipsy) September 23, 2017  That’s Charity Majors, a well known voice on Observability and someone who has built a business doing it well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of Moving Your WSO2 Deployment On to Kubernetes?</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-01-22_thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 19:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-01-22_thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Moving from a Virtual Machine based deployment to a Container Clustering environment can be quite a few sleepless nights. Cloud deployment artifacts for WSO2 products would reduce this number by a few, because of their tried and tested nature. These include Dockerfiles, Puppet based configurations, Kubernetes and Mesos deployment artifacts. As easy as these artifacts make life easier during a redesign stage of an existing deployment, let us anyway walk through some points to keep in mind regarding a WSO2 deployment on top of Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running WSO2 Products on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-02-09_running-wso2-products-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-02-09_running-wso2-products-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Running WSO2 Products on Kubernetes
 Please note that the following article has ‘expired’ in terms of accuracy when it comes to the artifacts used and the way things are done. WSO2 has made many improvements on top the configurations mentioned below and how to manipulate those artifacts might have been changed since.
 It’s 2016. Kubernetes needs no introduction. Neither does WSO2, so let’s get to the point. Let’s run WSO2 Identity Server on Kubernetes!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
