<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wso2 on chamila.dev</title>
    <link>https://chamila.dev/tags/wso2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wso2 on chamila.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 18:15:37 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://chamila.dev/tags/wso2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Design a WSO2 Docker Image</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-should-be-your-concerns-for-wso2-ondocker&#34;&gt;What should be your concerns for WSO2 on Docker?&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image_0.jpeg#layoutTextWidth&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chamila.dev/thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes-4e9a77b3377d&#34;&gt;Deploying WSO2 products on Containerized platforms&lt;/a&gt; is a well-tested well-resourced activity. There are various resources available to deploy WSO2 products on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/docker-apim&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/kubernetes-apim/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/pivotal-cf-apim&#34;&gt;CloudFoundry&lt;/a&gt;, AWS ECS, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wso2/dcos-apim&#34;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, both officially and unofficially. However, designing a Docker image so that optimal non-functional traits like performance, operational efficiency, and security is a separate topic in itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2018-12-24_how-to-design-a-wso2-docker-image_1.png#layoutTextWidth&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Options available to obtain WSO2 products other than downloading the Zip file itself (https://wso2.com/api-management/install/)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker, being both a DSL and a utility tool for Container image packaging, can be written in several different ways keeping various operational goals in mind. These approaches vary from an all files and configs pre-baked end to another end where almost everything, except a tiny helper layer, being mounted at Container run-time. However, not all these approaches are suitable for a WSO2 deployment, and figuring out these details can be a daunting task, especially at an earlier phase of the deployment. Therefore, it’s important to have a set of common &lt;strong&gt;guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;that can help determine which approach to take in each case. I emphasize the word &lt;strong&gt;guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; because these are only them, not hard rules or must-do’s in every deployment. There is freedom for the user to stray away, as long as the compromises made in doing so are understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing WSO2 Logs to Splunk from a Containerized Deployment</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-28_publishing-wso2-logs-to-splunk-from-a-containerized-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 09:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-28_publishing-wso2-logs-to-splunk-from-a-containerized-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;or-how-to-publish-to-splunk-from-any-docker-environment&#34;&gt;Or how to publish to Splunk from any Docker environment&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WSO2 products follow a standard structure when it comes to configuration, data, artifacts, and logging. Configuration files are found in &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/conf folder, data in &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/data, artifacts in &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/deployment (or in &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/tenants folder if you’re in to multi-tenancy). All the log files are written into &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/logs folder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;log-aggregation&#34;&gt;Log Aggregation&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All log events are output as entries to files through Log4J. Because of this, when it’s time to attach WSO2 logging to a log aggregator, it’s a matter of incorporating a tailing file reader agent and directing it towards &amp;lt;CARBON_HOME&amp;gt;/repository/logs folder. For an example, for ELK this could be something like &lt;strong&gt;FileBeat&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD APIs with WSO2 API Manager</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 03:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2018-11-25_cicd-apis-with-wso2-api-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-do-continuous-integration-and-continuous-delivery-of-apis-with-wso2-apimanager&#34;&gt;How to do continuous integration and continuous delivery of APIs with WSO2 API Manager&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wso2.com/api-management/&#34;&gt;WSO2 API Manager&lt;/a&gt;, the only &lt;a href=&#34;https://wso2.com/resources/analyst-reports/the-forrester-wave-api-management-solutions-q4-2018/?utm_source=bannerprodpg&amp;amp;utm_medium=mailer&amp;amp;utm_campaign=forrester_wave_apim_2018B2&#34;&gt;Open Source Leader in API Management Solutions in Forrester Wave&lt;/a&gt;, packs in a wide range of advanced API Management features that covers a number of end user stories. Through customization introduced to the extension points available throughout the product, WSO2 API Manager can be adopted to almost all API Management scenarios imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample: WSO2 EI Cache Mediator based Token Caching</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-11-12_sample-wso2-ei-cache-mediator-based-token-caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-11-12_sample-wso2-ei-cache-mediator-based-token-caching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post and the sample code are the results of a particular issue I had to tackle recently. Though the sample code is my own, the idea and the approach have many authors, arising from the collective knowledge on the WSO2 Middleware Stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-typical-case-forcaching&#34;&gt;The Typical Case for Caching&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Token based authentication is not a new paradigm. The basic story is,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to a Identity Management Service and obtain a token based on a kind of authentication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Call a service provider API, providing the token received in step #1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Service provider validates the token and acts on the privileges translated from the token&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2017-11-12_sample-wso2-ei-cache-mediator-based-token-caching_0.jpeg#layoutOutsetLeft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure as Code : AWS CloudFormation</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-07-03_infrastructure-as-code-aws-cloudformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 11:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-07-03_infrastructure-as-code-aws-cloudformation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog post is based on a talk I did on AWS CloudFormation as an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/8br68UFQtb7qpF&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; &#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-case-for-infrastructure-ascode&#34;&gt;The case for Infrastructure as Code&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a typical deployment of a software stack. The process might look like the following.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design solution architecture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Estimate infrastructure specs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure compute, network, and database resources manually&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy the applications and prepare databases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Test and ship&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple from the looks of it doesn’t it? The catch is this. This is just half of the solution maintenance. There are several more scenarios involved that can quickly turn this in to a complex fragile piece of engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballerina with Container Support</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-02-21_ballerina-with-container-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 06:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-02-21_ballerina-with-container-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chamila.dev/blog/img/2017-02-21_ballerina-with-container-support_0.png#layoutFillWidth&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WSO2 unveiled its latest contribution to the world of integration, Ballerina, yesterday during the &lt;a href=&#34;http://us17.wso2con.com/&#34;&gt;WSO2Con 2017 in San Fransisco&lt;/a&gt;. Ballerina is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ballerinalang.org/&#34;&gt;general purpose language with a focus on integration and a visual approach to coding&lt;/a&gt;. It’s strongly typed, integration friendly, and carries native support for a list of technologies such as support for REST, JSON, XML, Swagger, and “&lt;strong&gt;Connectors&lt;/strong&gt;” that communicate with Facebook, and Twitter etc. This write up will focus on Docker based Containerization of Ballerina programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of Moving Your WSO2 Deployment On to Kubernetes?</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-01-22_thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 19:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2017-01-22_thinking-of-moving-your-wso2-deployment-on-to-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving from a Virtual Machine based deployment to a Container Clustering environment can be quite a few sleepless nights. Cloud deployment artifacts for WSO2 products would reduce this number by a few, because of their tried and tested nature. These include Dockerfiles, Puppet based configurations, Kubernetes and Mesos deployment artifacts. As easy as these artifacts make life easier during a redesign stage of an existing deployment, let us anyway walk through some points to keep in mind regarding a WSO2 deployment on top of Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Upload a Carbon App (CAR File) to a Remote WSO2 Server</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-09-17_how-to-upload-a-carbon-app-car-file-to-a-remote-wso2-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-09-17_how-to-upload-a-carbon-app-car-file-to-a-remote-wso2-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Carbon Apps, or CAR Files are a deployable package consisting of WSO2 Product related artifacts. These artifacts can range from Synapse Sequences, Proxy Services, Registry items, to Dashboard Server Gadgets, Dashboards, Siddhi Execution Plans, to Tasks like Purging, NTask etc. For example, to group a set of artifacts to be deployed on WSO2 ESB, a CAR file can be used that has some Synapse Sequences, Proxy Services, APIs, and Endpoints. In essence, it’s a compressed Zip file with a different extension.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring WSO2 Logs with Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana (or Grafana)</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-09-10_monitoring-wso2-logs-with-elasticsearch-logstash-and-kibana-or-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 21:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-09-10_monitoring-wso2-logs-with-elasticsearch-logstash-and-kibana-or-grafana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently been doing some work involving analytics dashboards and the subject proved to be really interesting. It has a wide range starting from Big Data to UX. Starting at a point where you determine what kind of data is collected and what kind information you need to get out of the dashboard, going to data analysis and data processing (probably on top an engine like Apache Spark), it finalizes at the visualization stage which is really fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running WSO2 Products on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-02-09_running-wso2-products-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2016-02-09_running-wso2-products-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running WSO2 Products on Kubernetes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that the following article has ‘expired’ in terms of accuracy when it comes to the artifacts used and the way things are done. WSO2 has made many improvements on top the configurations mentioned below and how to manipulate those artifacts might have been changed since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s 2016. Kubernetes needs no introduction. Neither does WSO2, so let’s get to the point. Let’s run WSO2 Identity Server on Kubernetes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consuming a Service Secured by WSO2 ESB</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-19_consuming-a-service-secured-by-wso2-esb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-19_consuming-a-service-secured-by-wso2-esb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chamila.dev/securing-a-web-service-with-wso2-esb-8e0495383f00#.eawqzbwgi&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I explained the steps needed, although somewhat minimal, to secure an unsecured backend service with WSO2 ESB. In this post I will continue on to the client side of the communication explaining the minimal client needed to communicate with the secure proxy service we created and take a peak at the action going on under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;usernametoken&#34;&gt;UsernameToken&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in to the client side code let’s take a look at the WS-Policy for the UsernameToken security we applied to our service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing a Web Service With WSO2 ESB</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-18_securing-a-web-service-with-wso2-esb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-18_securing-a-web-service-with-wso2-esb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WSO2 Enterprise Service Bus is one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.samisa.org/2014/02/wso2-esb-performance-round-75.html&#34;&gt;best performing implementations&lt;/a&gt; for the Enterprise market. In this article I will briefly go through what it takes to secure an unsecured backend web service using WSO2 ESB as a mediator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security in Web Services is covered by the WS-Security standard. There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/ws-sx/security-policy/examples/ws-sp-usecases-examples-cd-01.html&#34;&gt;various policies&lt;/a&gt; such as simple username and password authentication and PKI certificates that can be used to secure a Web Service. The policy that will be used is described using the WS-Policy standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Web Service Using Apache Axis2</title>
      <link>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-01_creating-a-web-service-using-apache-axis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chamila.dev/blog/2014-07-01_creating-a-web-service-using-apache-axis2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need Apache Axis2 running and a suitable container. You could also run Axis2 as a standalone server but for this let’s use Tomcat as a container. So in the following order&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download and install Oracle JDK7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download and install Tomcat 7 (even 8 would do, but it seems as of now Tomcat 8 isn’t being supported by Eclipse, so let’s go with version 7)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download and install Axis2 on Tomcat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oracle-jdk7&#34;&gt;Oracle JDK7&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download and extract the JDK tarball.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
