<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apache stratos | nuts!]]></title>
  <link href="http://chamilad.github.io/blog/categories/apache-stratos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chamilad.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-17T10:07:11+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://chamilad.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[chamila de alwis]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Stratos Cartridge Agent: Day 0]]></title>
    <link href="http://chamilad.github.io/blog/2015/03/17/apache-stratos-cartridge-agent-contract/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-17T04:25:03+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://chamilad.github.io/blog/2015/03/17/apache-stratos-cartridge-agent-contract</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the first post of a series of comprehensive guide to the Apache Stratos Cartridge Agent, let&rsquo;s look at the Cartridge Agent contract. Keep tuned in and expect more detailed explanations on the instance and Cartridge Agent configuration, workflow different Cartridge Agent implementations, their configurations and newly introduced plugin system in the Python implementation.</p>

<h1>Role of the Cartridge Agent</h1>

<p>When the instances are spawned in Apache Stratos, there are a few requirements that the particular instance should fulfill. It should</p>

<ol>
<li>Listen to the message broker events that are intended to it and publish events notifying any listening parties of its current state (STARTED|ACTIVATED|MAINTENANCE_MODE etc)</li>
<li>Check if the intended ports of the instance are active or not and publish the status accordingly</li>
<li>Periodically check the health statistics of the instance and publish them to an expecting <a href="http://code.chamiladealwis.com/blog/2014/10/10/thrift-communication-in-apache-stratos/">Thrift compatible</a> Complex Event Processor</li>
<li>Clone from and constantly update an artifact repository if specified</li>
</ol>


<p>It&rsquo;s obvious that there should be an independent common component in each instance that fulfills these requests. And just like that, we&rsquo;ve stated the case for the cartridge agent.</p>

<h2>Message broker communication</h2>

<p>Apache Stratos has a loosely-coupled component structure which executes the major communication bulk over a message broker. This enables any new component to join the chit-chat without disrupting the ongoing communication or without any impact on the configuration of the existing components. Any component can go silent and it wouldn&rsquo;t affect the communication channel. The communication happens via message broker <em>Events</em> and <em>Topics</em> in the common communication channel. Therefore each component should only be aware of the location (and sometimes the credentials) of the common communication channel, the message broker.</p>

<p>The Cartridge Agent connects to the message broker, publishes its initial status and listens to the <em>topics</em> for any events that are important to it. We&rsquo;ll see what these events are and what their impact would be on the work flow of the agent in the walk through section.</p>

<h2>Ports activity check</h2>

<p>For each cartridge, a set of ports are defined in the cartridge definition. The intended services should run on these ports. The agent should determine if a the intended service is up or not before it can announce that it is ready to accept requests. It does so by checking if the specified ports are active or not.</p>

<h2>Health statistics publishing</h2>

<p>The Cloud is about Scale, and Scale is about Health. Apache Stratos auto-scaling feature takes care of the complex scaling requirements of the deployed services based on a number of parameters, on a number of levels. From the point of the instance, its contribution to the scaling effort should be to announce its health status to the decision making process.</p>

<p>The agent does this by collecting the memory usage and the load average values of the running instance and publishing them to a real time Complex Event Processor via Apache Thrift protocol. (Why doesn&rsquo;t it use the broker channel? Well, it&rsquo;s too darn slow to begin with for a real time event to be <em>real time</em>. Hammer and the problem anyone?) It does this periodically, usually every 15 seconds. If an instance stops publishing health stats events and stays dark for more than 60 seconds, the Complex Event Processor considers that instance to be a hopeless case and announces that an instance has gone dark. The auto-scaler, upon receiving this announcement (an <em>Event</em> published on a <em>topic</em> as you might have guessed), issues orders to terminate the faulty instance and spawn a new instance to take the place of the fallen comrade.</p>

<h2>Artifacts Distribution</h2>

<p>Most cartridge types deal with a set of artifacts that are hosted on a remote repository, that should be copied over to the instance and executed on. For an example a PHP cartridge will require a remote repository location to copy the web artifacts from. It is the Cartridge Agent that performs this artifact management task. In addition to cloning from the remote repository, there are cases where the locally modified artifacts should be pushed to the remote repository. This is also carried out by the Cartridge Agent.</p>

<p>It is the responsibility of the Cartridge Agent to manage all the tasks and make sure the instance goes through its intended life cycle. But, who configures and starts the Cartridge Agent? Keeping aside the philosophical overtone of that question, let&rsquo;s take a look at the instance configuration process in the next article before diving in to the Cartridge Agent life cycle itself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thrift Communication in Apache Stratos]]></title>
    <link href="http://chamilad.github.io/blog/2014/10/10/thrift-communication-in-apache-stratos/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-10T15:33:51+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://chamilad.github.io/blog/2014/10/10/thrift-communication-in-apache-stratos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Thrift Streaming Basics in WSO2 Carbon</h1>

<p>In Stratos, data publishing over Thrift is done via streaming. It uses WSO2 Carbon&rsquo;s Data Bridge to serialize data in to a stream and publish to a given Ip address and a Port. The use of DataBridge is explained <a href="http://wso2.com/library/articles/2012/07/creating-custom-agents-publish-events-bamcep/">here</a>.</p>

<h2>Stream Definition</h2>

<p>In order to publish data as a stream, the definition of the particular stream should be defined first. This is achieved using the <code>org.wso2.carbon.databridge.commons.StreamDefinition</code> class. The list of attributes that will be written to the stream is defined using a StreamDefinition object to be assigned to a particular DataPublisher.</p>

<p>One notable aspect of the StreamDefinition class is the three separate attribute list for metaData, correlationData and payloadData in that order. This separation of the attributes is a logical divide which doesn&rsquo;t have any significant meaning on the server side when it comes to WSO2 CEP and WSO2 BAM. It is available for the publisher to make sense of the various types of data that are being published and then later analyzed. This scenario in the WSO2 CEP context is explained <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26033755/what-is-meta-data-correlation-data-and-payload-data-in-wso2-cep">here</a>.</p>

<p>A StreamDefinition should minimally have a stream ID and a stream name. Additionally a nickname, and a description can be added. The stream ID is generated by the receiver when the StreamDefinition is associated with a particular connection. This constitutes of the stream name and the stream version. When publishing data this stream ID is used to retrieve the stream definition at the receiver&rsquo;s end. In fact the first two attributes to be published when publishing data are the stream ID of <code>STRING</code> type and the timestamp of the event in milliseconds of type <code>LONG</code>.</p>

<p>The attributes describing the data that is published have to added to the StreamDefinition <em>in the order they are to be published</em>. The order is important in a data stream because it is bound to the way the data is read from the receiver&rsquo;s side.</p>

<p>For each attribute added, the type of the data should be defined. WSO2 DataBridge provides readable attribute types that represents the <a href="http://thrift-tutorial.readthedocs.org/en/latest/thrift-types.html">type system in Thrift</a>, as <code>INT</code>, <code>LONG</code>, <code>FLOAT</code>, <code>DOUBLE</code>, <code>STRING</code> and <code>BOOL</code>.</p>

<h2>Data</h2>

<p>Data are written in to the stream as Events. <code>org.wso2.carbon.databridge.commons.Event</code> object stores the data for a particular event and when the time comes to actually serialize the data in to the wire, <code>org.wso2.carbon.databridge.agent.thrift.internal.utils.ThriftEventConverter</code> adds all the data together and assigns proper Thrift types to each data. This logic is implemented in the Carbon platform&rsquo;s DataBridge.</p>

<h1>Usage Scenarios</h1>

<p>Apache Stratos publishes data over Thrift in two scenarios. Both scenarios are involved with managing cartridges based on their performance. Cartridge Agent initiates and manages streaming of data from the cartridge to the monitoring server/complex event processing server. The addresses and the credentials of the data aggregation servers should be provided from Stratos to the cartridge agent.</p>

<h2>Health Statistics Publishing</h2>

<p><img src="/images/post_resource/thrift/healthstats.jpg"></p>

<p>Health statistics of a particular cartridge instance is used by a real time processing engine to declare events that manage the cartridge life cycle. For example based on the memory load and the CPU usage, CEP can publish events that the AutoScaling picks up and accordingly spawn new instances. Another example is the AutoScaler terminating faulty cartridges based on events published by the CEP when health statistics publishing stops for a certain period of timeout. The role of the AutoScaler along with a CEP is described <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/STRATOS/4.1.0+Auto-scaler">here</a>.</p>

<p>Following values should be passed to the Cartridge Agent via the Puppet Configuration, which includes these values as system properties when the Cartridge Agent starts up. They are then used to establish the connection and publish the data to the Thrift receiver.</p>

<ol>
<li>Ip address (<code>thrift.receiver.ip</code>)</li>
<li>Port (<code>thrift.receiver.port</code>) &ndash; 7711 is the default value</li>
<li>Username(<code>thrift.server.admin.username</code>)</li>
<li>Password(<code>thrift.server.admin.password</code>)</li>
</ol>


<p>The Cartridge Agent publishes several events to the message broker after it starts, two key events being the InstanceStartedEvent and the InstanceActivatedEvent. The InstanceStartedEvent is published after the Topology is confirmed as consistent. The InstanceActivatedEvent is published after the InstanceStartedEvent, but this can happen in two code paths. If there is no repository based artifact management to be done, the InstanceActivatedEvent will be published immediately by the CartridgeAgent. If the Cartridge Agent has to wait for the ArtifactUpdatedEvent to start managing the artifacts related to a repository, the InstanceActivatedEvent will be published after the artifacts are synchronized to the instance. These events are published from the Cartridge Agent to the <code>/instance/status</code> topic in the message broker. In both cases the health statistics publishing job starts after the InstanceActivatedEvent is published. The interval at which the health statistics publishing job works can be adjusted by specifying <code>stats.notifier.interval</code> property of the cartridge agent. By default this is set to 15 seconds.</p>

<p>The health statistics are published with the stream name <code>cartridge_agent_health_stats</code>. The stream definition contains only the payload data and the types of the added payload data are as follows.</p>

<ol>
<li>&ldquo;cluster_id&rdquo;           => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;network_partition_id&rdquo; => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;member_id&rdquo;            => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;partition_id&rdquo;         => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;health_description&rdquo;   => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;value&rdquo;                => DOUBLE</li>
</ol>


<p>Two types of health statistics are published by the cartridge agent, percentage of free memory, and the load average of the CPU. <code>health_description</code> field uses values <code>memory_consumption</code> and <code>load_average</code> respectively for these two readings.</p>

<p>Health statistics publishing can be disabled by setting <code>cep.stats.publisher.enabled</code> property of the Cartridge agent to <code>false</code>.</p>

<h2>Log Publishing</h2>

<p><img src="/images/post_resource/thrift/logs.jpg"></p>

<p>The application logs are published to a monitoring server by the cartridge agent for data analysis. For this the property <code>enable.data.publisher</code> should be set to <code>true</code>.</p>

<p>The log publishing thread starts as soon as the cartridge agent initialization is complete. For it to connect to the Thrift receiver following fields have to be passed to the Cartridge Agent.</p>

<ol>
<li>Ip address (<code>monitoring.server.ip</code>)</li>
<li>Port (<code>monitoring.server.port</code>)</li>
<li>Secure Port (<code>monitoring.server.secure.port</code>)</li>
<li>Username (<code>monitoring.server.admin.username</code>)</li>
<li>Password (<code>monitoring.server.admin.password</code>)</li>
</ol>


<p>The stream definition for the log publishing is as follows. Note that one metaData attribute is added to the definition by the publisher. This contains the member ID of the particular instance that is publishing the data.</p>

<h4>MetaData</h4>

<ol>
<li>&ldquo;memberId&rdquo;   => STRING</li>
</ol>


<h4>PayloadData</h4>

<ol>
<li>&ldquo;tenantID&rdquo;   => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;serverName&rdquo; => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;appName&rdquo;    => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;logTime&rdquo;    => LONG</li>
<li>&ldquo;priority&rdquo;   => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;message&rdquo;    => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;logger&rdquo;     => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;ip&rdquo;         => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;instance&rdquo;   => STRING</li>
<li>&ldquo;stacktrace&rdquo; => STRING</li>
</ol>


<p>The log publisher stream is defined with the name of format <code>logs.{tenantId}.{cartridgeAlias}.yyyy.MM.dd</code>.</p>

<p>For each of the log that is mentioned under <code>log.file.paths</code> parameter a separate <code>org.apache.stratos.cartridge.agent.data.publisher.log.FileBasedLogPublisher</code> thread is started.</p>

<p>The FileBasedLogPublisher scans the log file for new lines and for each new line added, publishes a new Event to the Thrift receiver. Therefore there is no defined interval for the log publisher naturally.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
