<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Load Balancing on blog.chamila.dev</title>
    <link>https://blog.chamila.dev/tags/load-balancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Load Balancing on blog.chamila.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:56:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.chamila.dev/tags/load-balancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Balancing and Reverse Proxying for Kubernetes Services</title>
      <link>https://blog.chamila.dev/post/2019-02-28_load-balancing-and-reverse-proxying-for-kubernetes-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chamila.dev/post/2019-02-28_load-balancing-and-reverse-proxying-for-kubernetes-services/</guid>
      <description>Different load balancing and reverse proxying strategies to use in Production K8s Deployments to expose services to outside traffic In this post, I’m going to tackle a topic that any K8s novice would start to think about, once they have cleared the basic concepts. **How would one go about exposing the services deployed inside a K8s cluster to outside traffic?**The content and some of the diagrams I’ve used in the post are from an internal tech talk I conducted at WSO2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Self-Signed SSL Certificate to AWS ACM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chamila.dev/post/2017-10-17_adding-a-selfsigned-ssl-certificate-to-aws-acm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 18:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chamila.dev/post/2017-10-17_adding-a-selfsigned-ssl-certificate-to-aws-acm/</guid>
      <description>When setting up AWS Load Balancers (Classic Load Balancers or Application Load Balancers), after adding a HTTPS transport, an SSL Certificate should be added so that SSL termination can be done at the Load Balancer. Here, for development purposes, the certificate added can be a self-signed one.
However if you try to upload a self-signed SSL Certificate to IAM or ACM using the AWS Web Console during Load Balancer creation, you will frequently come across an error similar to the following.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>